Preliminary Inventory of the Felix Vladimirovich Volkhovskiĭ papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Felix Vladimirovich Volkhovskiĭ papers
1875-1914
67046
Hoover Institution Archives
18 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes (13.5 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, photographs, periodicals, and clippings relating to revolutionary movements in Imperial Russia.
Volkhovskīĭ, Felix Vladimirovich, 1846-1914
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1967.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Russian revolutionist and journalist; Socialist Revolutionary Party leader; editor, Free Russia (London).
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, writings, photographs, periodicals, and clippings relating to revolutionary movements in Imperial Russia.
Partiia sotsialistov-revoliutsionerov.; Revolutionaries--Russia.; Russia--History.; Russia.; Socialism--Russia.
- Correspondence, 1875-1914
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes some other materials.
  - Aitov, D., 1910 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Alisov, P., 1894 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Amfiteatrov, A., 1910-1912 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Argunov, A., 1914 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Balamez, G., 1894 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    Includes 1 note.
  - Bakh, A., 1905-1910 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Belogolovyi, Mr., 1894 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Bervi-Flerovskii, V., 1894 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Breshko-Breshkovskaia, Ekaterina Konstantinovna, 1904-1905 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    Includes 1 clipping from American press and letter from Helma S. Dudley to Breshkovskaya.
  - Burtsev, Vladimir, 1894-1904
    - Manuscripts (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - Notes on Bakunin; various notes, 1895 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - Letters, 1894-1904 (Box-folder 1: 12)
    - Various letters and telegrams relating to Burtsev's arrest in England, 1897-1898 (Box-folder 1: 13)
    - Letter, articles and court papers relating to Burtsev's arrest in England, 1897-1898, undated (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Varshavskii, A., 1896 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Vodovozov, V., 1912 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Voinich, V., 1892-1894 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Volkhovsky, F., 1890-1893 (Box-folder 1: 18)
    Includes 2 notes.
  - Volkov, E., 1912-1914 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Goldenberg, L., 1891-1895 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Goncharenki, Agapii, 1890 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Gorki, M. and Pechkova, E., undated (Box-folder 1: 22)
    Includes manuscript.
  - Gots, M., 1904 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Grozovskii, L., 1894 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Gronkovskii, K.,; Beitner, L.,; Kuznetsoff, A., 1894-1899 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Gurvich, I., 1893-1894 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Debagorii-Mokrievich, V., 1894-1895 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Dobrodjanu, K., 1894 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Dragomanov, M.,; Pavlik, Mikhailo, 1894-1903 (Box-folder 1: 29-30)
    Includes notes by E. Lazarev and S. Krasnopol'skii about Dragomanov's brochure, Nevolia Very.
  - Evalenko, A. M., 1894-1895 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - Zhitlovskii, Kh., 1894-1897 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Zhuk-Baturinskii, Vasilii, 1894-1904 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Zasulich, V. I., 1894 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    Includes letter to her sister, I. I. Uspenskii, and letters from unknown persons about creating a common organ, with Plekanov, etc.
  - Kashintsev, I., 1893-1903 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Klementz, D., 1875-1876 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Kolosov, E., 1908 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Kornilov, S., 1908 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Korolenko, V., 1893 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    Includes English translation of the manuscript "The Forest Blusters."
  - Kotziubinskii, M., 1912 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Kochenkova, A., 1894-1895 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Kropotkin, P., 1893-1913
    - Letters, 1880-1913 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1893 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Kurnatovskii, V., 1895 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Lazarev, E., 1890-1913
    - Various letters, 1890-1914 (Box-folder 2: 12-13)
      Includes 2 to Plekhanov, Georgii Valentinovich, 1896.
    - Archive of his American period, 1890-1894 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Lavrov, P. L., 1896
    - Letters, 1896 (Box-folder 2: 15)
      Includes copy of his letter to Tverkoi, May 14, 1896.
    - Manuscript of his article, "Istoriia I Russkie Revoliutsionery" (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Lebedev, V., 1907-1914 (Box-folder 2: 17)
    Includes many letters concerning the publication of Za Narod.
  - Lopatin, German,; Lopatin, Vsevolod,; Lopatin, N.,; Bart, Bruno (son of G. Lopatin), 1893-1914 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Lukashewicz, A., 1913 (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Luxemburg, R., 1893-1895 (Box-folder 2: 20)
  - Liadov, I., 1894 (Box-folder 2: 21)
  - Martov, L., 1913 (Box-folder 2: 22)
  - Minor, O., 1904 (Box-folder 2: 23)
  - Miroliubov, V., 1912 (Box-folder 2: 24)
  - Moinsenko, B., 1914 (Box-folder 2: 25)
  - Nogorskii, V., 1895-1896 (Box-folder 2: 26)
  - Natanson, M., 1913-1914 (Box-folder 2: 27)
  - Osinov, V., 1892-1894 (Box-folder 2: 28)
  - Perekrestov, N., 1891-1894 (Box-folder 2: 29)
  - Polivanov, P. (letter about his suicide), 1903 (Box-folder 2: 30)
  - Preluker, Y., undated (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Prisbylev, A., 1908 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - Rakitnikov, N., 1911-1912 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Ralli-Arbore, Z., 1902 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    Includes 5 letters about Potyomkintsy in Romania.
  - Rappoport, Ch., 1892-1897 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - Rubanovich, I., 1904-1914 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Russel'-Sudzilovskii, N., 1891-1903 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Sabsovich, G. K., 1890-1891 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Savinkov, V., 1912 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Semenov, E. P., 1903-1904 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Sinegub, L., 1904-1909 (Box-folder 3: 11)
  - Smirnov, V. N., 1893 (Box-folder 3: 12)
  - Soskis, David, 1895-1911, undated (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - Stepniak-Kravchinskii, S., 1894-1896
    - Letters, 1894 (Box-folder 3: 14)
    - Various letters and telegrams relating to his death in 1895 (Box-folder 3: 15)
    - Various letters and newspaper articles relating to his death in 1985 (Box-folder 3: 16)
    - Correspondence between Kropotkin and Volkhovsky re S-K, 1896 (Box-folder 3: 17)
      Includes letters from Kravchinskii, Fanni; Chaikovskii, N. V.; Krigorino, P.; Krapotkin I, P.; Volkhovsky, F., books and copies; Shishko, L.; Teplov, A. L.
  - Stone, N., 1893-1894 (Box-folder 3: 18)
  - Sun Yat-Sen, 1897 (Box-folder 3: 19)
  - Tan-Bogoraz, V., 1907 (Box-folder 3: 20)
  - Tverskoi-Dementev (Demens), 1895-1896 (Box-folder 3: 21)
  - Tolstoy, L., 1895 (Box-folder 3: 22)
    Includes copy of a letter to Lazarev, copies of 3 letters by Lazarev to Tolstoy, and 1 letter by a Tolstovets (follower), undated.
  - Figner, Vera, 1908-1914 (Box-folder 3: 23)
  - Frederickson, N. C., 1903-1904 (Box-folder 3: 24)
  - Khristoforov, A. X., 1897-1898 (Box-folder 3: 25)
    Includes manuscript obituary written by Volkhovsky.
  - Tsebrikova, M., 1888-1889 (Box-folder 3: 26)
  - Chaikovskii, Nikolai, 1893-1910 (Box-folder 3: 27)
    Includes pamphlet on his arrest in Russia, 1908.
  - Chertkov, V., 1895 (Box-folder 3: 28)
  - Chudnovskii, S. L., 1912 (Box-folder 3: 29)
  - Shishko, Leonid E., 1893-1910
    - Letters, 1893-1910 (Box-folder 3: 30)
    - Drafts on "Fund of Free Russian Press,", 1894 (Box-folder 3: 31)
    - Biographical data on Shishko (Box-folder 3: 32)
  - Elpidin, M., 1894-1896 (Box-folder 3: 33)
  - Yakubovich, P., 1908 (Box-folder 3: 34)
  - Finland, 1902-1908
    - Aminov, P., 1903 (Box-folder 3: 35)
    - Zilliacus, Konni, 1902-1904 (Box-folder 3: 36)
    - Neoviduz, A., undated (Box-folder 3: 37)
    - Various letters, 1905-1908 (Box-folder 3: 38)
  - Ukraine, 1890-1912
    - Kassacz, Larissa (Lesa Ukrainka), 1902-1903 (Box-folder 3: 39)
    - Various letters, 1890-1910 (Box-folder 3: 40)
      Includes 1 leaflet.
    - The Ruthenian Question, 1912 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Poland, 1892-1895
    - Bohdanowicz, Floryan, 1893-1894 (Box-folder 4: 2)
    - Czarlinski, V., 1892 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - Grigorjev, Mr., 1894 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - Jodko, V., 1895 (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - Lutoslawskii, Wincety, 1895 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - Dombrowskii, P., manuscript of his biography (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - Kaniowsky, J., acknowledgement of a contribution for the benefit of striking workers (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - Military School for Russian Socialists, 1913
    - Ovich, S., 1913 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - Letters of Vigen (Armenian Socialist),; Pilsudskii, I.,; Filipowicz, T.,; visiting card of Wronski, A. (Jodko), 1913 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Russian Volunteers in Balkan War, 1912-1914
    - Astafev, A., 1913 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - Ykatev (?), 1912 (Box-folder 4: 12)
    - Libert, A., 1912-1913 (Box-folder 4: 13)
    - Petrov, A., 1912-1913 (Box-folder 4: 14)
    - Tarasenka, N., 1913 (Box-folder 4: 15)
    - Vultur, leaflet-poem (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Project Platform Voennago Soiuza, 1910 (Box-folder 4: 17)
    Manuscript.
  - Disputes between S-R and S.D., 1902-1904 (Box-folder 4: 18)
    Includes manuscript by Chaikovskii, N.
  - S-R documents, 1903-1910 (Box-folder 4: 19)
    Includes document on Vladivostok Uprising, 1907.
  - Preparation for Uprising, 1905 (Box-folder 4: 20)
    Documents.
  - Izvestiia Oblastnogo Komiteta Zagranichnykh Organizatsii Sotsialistov Revolutsionerov, Paris, Nos. 2 and 6, 1908 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Kornev, A., editor of Golos Truda, Kiev, 1913 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - S-R party. Various materials (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - International Socialist Congress, Copenhagen, 1910 (Box-folder 4: 24)
    Includes manuscript "Doklad Sotsialistov Revolutsionerov" and resolutions.
  - Manuscript on the history of the S-R party (Box-folder 4: 25)
  - Various letters, 1900-1913 (Box-folder 4: 26)
  - Various letters and documents, 1890-1914 (Box-folder 4: 27)
  - Transfer of illegal literature, relating to financing the escape of political prisoners, circa 1900 (Box-folder 4: 28)
- Hard labor camps and exiles, 1888-1908 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  Letters and manuscripts.
- Irkutsk massacre, 1889 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  Manuscript and documents.
- Case of Paris bombists, 1892-1893 (Box-folder 5: 2)
- Student movements, 1890 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  Various letters and documents.
- Dukhobory, 1895 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  Letters.
- Potemkintsy, undated (Box-folder 5: 5)
  Various letters.
- Union of Black Sea Fleet, Seamen, 1911-1913
  - Adamovich, M. D. (Karl), 1911-1913 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    Various letters and documents. Includes letters from Anichkin, 1912.
  - Arrest of Adamovich, M. D., 1913 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    Letters and clippings.
  - Manuscript about the union, 1912 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Famine in Russia, undated (Box-folder 5: 9)
    Manuscript and document.
- Society of Friends of Russian Freedom, 1890-1913
  - Baker, John, 1893 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Barrows, J. C., 1905 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Beard, Mary S., 1894 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1903 (Box-folder 5: 13)
    Includes 1 clipping.
  - Braitsford, H. N., 1905 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Ferreri, G., 1894 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Fraser, Scott, 1894 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Frost, George, 1890 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Galsworthy, J., undated (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Galvani, William, 1890 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - Green, J. P., 1905 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Heater, M. R., 1893-1894 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - Hyndman, M., 1908 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Kennan, George, 1891-1911 (Box-folder 5: 23)
    Includes portraits of Mr. and Mrs. Kennan and photograph of their cottage.
  - King, J., 1908 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - King, Mackenzi, 1911 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Macdonald, Mr. (Presbyterian Minister), 1896 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Macdonald, James Ramsay, 1905 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Mallet, Gertrude, 1893-1902 (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - Perris, H., 1892-1908 (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - Perris, G. H., undated (Box-folder 5: 30)
    Manuscript about Tolstoy in England.
  - Peters, M. R., 1904 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - Prescott, Constance, 1903 (Box-folder 5: 32)
  - Roper, Reginald E., 1894 (Box-folder 5: 33)
  - Scott-Saxton, Mrs., 1890-1894 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Spence-Watson, R., 1892-1909 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    Includes 1 photograph.
  - Sidgewick, Charlotte, 1890-1900 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Thomas, Elizabeth, 1894-1896 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Thompson, Herbert, 1894 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Travers, Rosalind, 1913 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Wells, H. G., 1908 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Various letters (in English), 1891-1913 (Box-folder 6: 8-12)
  - Banquet to Liebknecht, London, 1899 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Schweizerischer Gewerkschaftsbund, Zurich, 1894 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Various letters and documents, undated (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Manuscript of a history of the Society of Friends of Russian Freedom in London, and other notes (Box-folder 6: 16)
- Editorial office of Za Narod, 1912-1914
  - Efimov, N., undated (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Mandel'berg, V., 1914 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Rubakin, A. N., undated (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - Rubanovich, I., 1913 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Rodshtein, L., 1913-1914 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Serzhant, 1912 (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Shtakhel'berg, S., 1914 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Dal'nii, A., undated (Box-folder 6: 24)
    Poems.
  - Zatermtogo, A. (?) (Novikov-Priboi) (Box-folder 6: 25)
    Two manuscripts.
  - Numerous manuscripts and archival material (Box-folder 6: 26, 7: 1-7)
  - Numerous manuscripts (Box-folder 7: 8-11, 8: 1-4)
- Fund of Free Russian Press, 1892-1903
  - Material on the history of the Fund (Box-folder 8: 5)
    Includes report.
  - Freies Russland (German edition of Free Russia), 1893-1894 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    Includes letters and documents.
  - Society of Popular Lectures in Eastland, London, 1903 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Case of Mendelson-Kasprzak, St., 1892-1895 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Numerous manuscripts (Box-folder 8: 9-12, 9: 1-3)
  - Pamphlets (Box-folder 9: 4-6)
    - Narodnyi Universitet v g. Tomsk
    - Kapital Sel'skikh Bezplatnyk Bibliotek v Sibiri
    - Gordovita Para opovidannia Petra Zabotsnia
    - S. M. Stepniak-Krawtschinski
    - Volkhovsky, F., At the Mercy of Every Official
    - Volkhovskoi, Skazka pro Tsaria Semena
    - Shishko, Chego khochet dobit'sia pravitel'stvo zakonom 9 noiabria
    - Gonenia na Dukhobortsev s zakliucheniem grafa L. Tolstogo
    - Koe-chto o Nashikh zadachakh, Po Voennym Voprosam
    - Dragomanov, M., Povisti Osipa Fed'kovicha
    - Pis'ma T. G. Shevchenka k B. Zaleskomu M. T. Simonov (Nomis) Rasskasy
    - Narodovolets: Numbers 1 -3 (2 copies of issue no. 3)
  - Various periodicals (Box-folder 9: 7-11)
    Includes other material.
- Correspondence on transportation of illegal literature to Russia, 1893-1897
  - Stepanov, P. (Pernskoy) (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Various correspondence with the Fund of Free Russian Press, circa 1890-1900 (Box-folder 9: 13, 10: 1-3)
  - Various letters, circa 1890-1900 (Box-folder 10: 4-11)
- Biographical file, 1896-1938
  - Numerous manuscripts (Box-folder 11: 1-8, 12: 1-11, 13: 1-9)
  - Letters to Volkhovsky from his daughter Vera, 1893-1913 (Box-folder 14: 1)
  - Letters from F. Volkhovsky to his daughter Vera (Box-folder 14: 2-3)
  - Various letters to Vera (Box-folder 14: 4-6)
  - Various photographs of revolutionaries (Box-folder 15: 1-7, 16: 1-2)
  - Postcards and prints, undated (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1900-1905 (Box-folder 16: 4-6, 17: 1)
  - Admissions card to Basel Socialist Congress, two telegrams regretting F. F. Volkhovsky's being unable to attend Breshkovskaia's 70th birthday in Paris, January 1914 (in French and Russian), 1912 November 24-26 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Biographical sketches (Box-folder 17: 3)
    Includes "Sketches," 9 pages in English; 4 pages in English and Russian; 2 1/2 pages in Russian; pamphlet At the Mercy of Every Official. Friends of Russian Freedom, London, 1890.
  - Correspondence between F. F. Volkhovsky and W. G. Fitzgerald, editor of Strand Magazine, 1898 February 19 - May 20 (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - Proofs of "How a Russian Escaped from Siberia" with correspondence dated November 189(?) (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Correspondence between Volkhovsky and Mr. and Mrs. Mallet, and between F. V. and John R. Åström, 1895 February 4,1895 February 10, 1896 October 6-7 (Box-folder 17: 6-7)
  - Correspondence from Michel Michailovsky (Moscow and Bedford Park), undated (Box-folder 17: 8)
  - Letters and cards from Russia (Box-folder 17: 9)
    Includes letter addressed to "Mr. G. George" (i.e., Egor Lazarev), dated October 21, 1895; letter addressed to "Rev. John R. Fleming" (i.e., Mrs. E. L. Voynich), dated October 12, 1894.
  - Manuscript drafts of tribute to Nikolai Konstantin Michailovsky (Populist Narodnic Patriarch), and Chaikovsky or Goldenberg on his "Jubilee,", 1900 November 28 (Box-folder 17: 10)
  - Documents and letters (Box-folder 17: 11)
    Includes U.S. passport of Ida Rauh (dated Vienna, August 30, 1906) left to be used by any suitable revolutionary or connection so long as it should not be for terrorist purposes, used by Vera Volkhovsky in 1906; certificate of recommendation, by a solicitor, November 26, 1902; city of Glasgow permit for travel to Russia, June 21, 1893; legal opinion about "false pretences in obtaining a passport" dated May 31, 1895 (includes Foreign Office memorandum, 1901, and legal opinion about marriage of foreigners in U.K.); letter from J. Spiridion of Cardiff relating to false passport application, dated February 8, 1895; letter from T. H. Sanderson of Foreign Office relating to imprisoned British subject Harry Williams of Central News Telgraphic Agency, dated May 29, 1895.
  - Personal souvenirs (Box-folder 17: 12)
    Includes a lock of hair of F. Volkhovsky's hair; F. Volkhovsky's wife's wedding ring (made from iron of political prisoner's leg iron); F. Volkhovsky's key chain; "Sergias" (Stepniak-Kravchinsky's watchguard); piece of a calendar page, October 27; a Soviet commemorative stamp, 1917-1923; and two post office seals.
  - Exercise books containing penciled writings by Vera Volkhovsky, with some addition by Felix Volkhovsky ("of one man's life") in Russian (Box-folder 17: 13)
  - Pocket diaries (in English, with some Russian entries), 1894-1898 (Box-folder 17: 14-16, 18: 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, bills, notes and correspondence (sometimes addressed to Volkhovsky's pseudonyms) (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Correspondence from two firms of solicitors (Radford and Frankland, and Rowe and May), relating to alleged slander by Inspector Melville, 1898 January 11 - February 5 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Album dedicated to George Kennan (Box-folder 20: 1)
    Inscribed "From a socialist to an American free-thinker and golden-hearted man, as a slight token of esteem. Do not forget us, George Kennan." 16 large pages comprised of autographed copy of F. Volkhovsky's poem "Our Oppressors", Peter and Paul Fortress, 1869; 6 1/2 full pages of print, extracted from the Siberian Gazette; a long manuscript tale (1883); and two poems, "Gold" of 1872 and "Patience" published anonymously 1871 (two pages missing). Apparently not presented to Kennan.
  - Various letters and correspondence (Box-folder 18: 5-6)
  - Periodicals, 1886-1890 (Box 21, Box-folder 22: 1-2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 19: 1-3)
  - Photographs (Box-folder 20: 2, 22: 3-6)
  - Magazines (Box-folder 20: 3-5, 22: 7)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box-folder 19: 4-7, 20: 6-8)
  - Photographs and illustrations (Box-folder 20: 9-11)
  - 3 University certificates for Vera Volkhovsky, 1899 (Box-folder 20: 12)
  - Pontings department store wrapping paper (Box-folder 19: 8)